Luke Powers

■ lukespowers@gmail.com In Luke Powers 🐶 lukepow.github.io 🗘 lukepow 📞 4807372137

PROFILE

I'm a full-stack software engineer with multiple years of experience in both the Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems. Over the past 2 years, I've built a solid foundation in web engineering fundamentals that I'm eager to deploy on challenging projects that expand my current skill set and tech stack. Most recently I co-created Snowclone, an open-source BaaS with real-time capabilities.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Snowclone *⊘*

2024 – present

Snowclone is an open-source project that streamlines the process of creating and managing cloud infrastructure for database and APIs that support frontend applications and require real-time capabilities.

- Developed a containerized architecture for portable backends that provides APIs for schema migration, REST, and real-time notifications using a PostgreSQL database (Node.js, express, SSE, Docker)
- Designed a cloud deployment architecture that prioritizes scalability and cost-efficiency (ECS Fargate, ELB, RDS)
- Leveraged Terraform to provision the 55 resources needed for each instance and to manage the state of projects deployed to AWS
- Built a CLI for managing the lifecycle of projects in AWS via terraform
- Authored a comprehensive technical case-study detailing the problem domain, system design, and engineering decisions
- Collaborated remotely with a team of four engineers using agile workflow

Software Engineer, Self-employed

2022 - 2023

Developed freelance and open-source applications including:

- Requestbin tool for collecting and debugging webhooks (DO Droplet, MongoDB, Nginx, React, Express)
- *Climbr* A tool for posting and viewing rock climbing routes and areas (Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL)

Capital Markets Analyst, CapCenter

2021 – 2022 | Richmond, VA

- Built and maintained dynamic pricing model and various reports to increase visibility of KPIs
- Achieved cost savings of >20% for the DM marketing channel by analyzing attribution and improving campaign targeting

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript, Ruby, Golang, Python, SQL

Libraries/Frameworks

Node.js, Express, React, Sinatra

Cloud

AWS, Terraform, Digital Ocean, Heroku

Other

Git/Github, Docker, Jest, HTTP/S, Websockets, SSE, OOP, REST APIs, Visual Studio

EDUCATION

Launch School 2022 – 2023

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum. Read more at launchschool.com/employers ${\mathscr O}$

University of Richmond,

2016 – 2020 | Richmond, VA

BS Business Administration, Finance Concentration